<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
				<funder ref="#_mJD4BqA">
					<orgName type="full">U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Science, Office of Basic Energy Sciences, Materials Sciences and Engineering Division</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_hrqmqtj">
					<orgName type="full">Office of Science, Office of Basic Energy Sciences</orgName>
				</funder>
				<funder ref="#_j9B646Z">
					<orgName type="full">U.S. Department of Energy</orgName>
				</funder>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California at Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Materials Sciences Division</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Materials Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California at Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>94720</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">National Center for Electron Microscopy</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>Molecular Foundry</addrLine>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Army Research Laboratory</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>2800 Powder Mill Road</addrLine>
									<postCode>94720 20783</postCode>
									<settlement>Berkeley Adelphi</settlement>
									<region>CA MD</region>
									<country>USA US USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">AB831F36A0254C7E8F13D58E9FCC5813</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1038/s41467-017-00516-5</idno>
					<note type="submission">Received: 27 February 2017 Accepted: 5 July 2017</note>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.1" ident="GROBID" when="2024-11-03T18:40+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract/>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Here, ri = xie1 + yie2 is the (2D) vector describing the position of atom i (e1 and e2 are the unit vectors defining the coordinate system), 𝑉 o is the depth of the potential minima, 𝑎 o is the equilibrium spring length (measured in units of 𝑎 s ), and the first sum is taken over nearest neighbors, counting each spring once.</p><p>The effects of thermal expansion mismatch are then explored as follows. A finite triangular shaped sample is defined. The initial configuration has each atom at a minimum of the substrate potential. A small random component is added to the positions of each atom, and the total potential energy of the system is then minimized. After minimization, the equilibrium length of the springs connecting the atoms, 𝑎 o , is reduced by a small amount (0.001 in dimensionless units), and the energy minimization is carried out again, using Mathematica's FindMinimum function with the initial positions chosen to be the positions found from the prior minimization. This process is repeated until the final value of 𝑎 o = 0.99.</p><p>In this model, the initial state corresponds to the growth temperature of the material. It is assumed that at the growth temperature, the materials are lattice matched. This is, in general, not true. However, for the case of the amorphous substrate, this is probably a reasonable assumption, as the growing film is not likely strained at the growth temperature. The reduction in the equilibrium spring length, then, is meant to model the thermal contraction of the WSe2 film relative to the substrate. A reduction of 1% in the spring length is comparable to the thermal expansion mismatch between WSe2 and SiO2.</p><p>The model is then used to explore the amplitude of the substrate corrugation required to retain the thermal mismatch strain. The amplitude of the substrate potential, 𝑉 o , is reduced to the point where it can no longer sustain a 1% strain in the film. It is important to note that this strain (1)  is sample size dependent, with larger samples requiring smaller, on average, corrugations to sustain the strain. Accordingly, we have considered an equilateral triangular sample containing 45,451 "atoms," with an edge length of approximately 100 nm (this corresponds to minimizing a function of roughly 91,000 variables, exploration of larger sizes is computationally more difficult). We considered a range of potential energy corrugation amplitudes, 𝑉 o . For 𝑉 o &lt;&lt; 1, an example of the pattern of relaxation that we observe is shown in Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">1 (b</ref>). Here, the imposed thermal mismatch strain is 0.8% biaxial. The strain plotted is defined to be (</p><p>) (𝜀 𝑥𝑥 + 𝜀 𝑦𝑦 ), with</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">𝜀 𝑖𝑗 = (<label>1 2</label></formula><p>) (</p><formula xml:id="formula_2">𝜕𝑢 𝑖 𝜕𝑥 𝑗 + 𝜕𝑢 𝑗 𝜕𝑥 𝑖</formula><p>), and 𝑢 𝑖 the 𝑖th component of the displacement. The sample displays an interesting strain pattern. The interior of the sample retains much of the thermal mismatch strain, though the strain is not perfectly uniform. The edges of the sample show a clear strain relaxation.</p><p>Through trial and error, we discovered that a potential corrugation amplitude of 𝑉 o ≈ 5 <ref type="bibr">× 10 -4</ref> was sufficient to retain the substrate lattice parameter over most of the sample (the results are shown in Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">1 (b)</ref>). Recall that this amplitude is measured in units of</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">1 2 𝜅𝑎 s 2 .</formula><p>If one can compute the value of</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">1 2</formula><p>𝜅𝑎 s 2 for WSe2, one can then assess the level of corrugation needed to sustain the thermal mismatch strain in the sample.</p><p>A value of</p><formula xml:id="formula_5">1 2</formula><p>𝜅𝑎 s 2 representing the properties of WSe2 can be found as follows. Consider a spring network as shown in Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> (a). There are three springs per lattice point, and under a biaxial strain of -0.7% measured from their equilibrium length, they have a strain energy per unit cell of approximately:</p><formula xml:id="formula_6">𝐸 strain = 3 1 2 𝜅𝑎 s 2 (0.007) 2</formula><p>This strain energy can be compared with the strain energy of the WSe2 monolayer under equivalent strain.</p><p>(2)</p><p>To compute the strain energy of the WSe2 monolayer, we employ linear elasticity theory.</p><p>The lattice parameter and elastic constants for WSe2 are computed as discussed below, arriving at the values 𝐶 11 = 120 J m -2 and 𝐶 12 = 23 J m -2 , and 𝑎 o = 3.361 Å. Note that since the elastic constants represent the elastic properties of a 2D material, they have dimension of energy per area.</p><p>Noting that the elastic energy of the film computed under a biaxial strain of 𝜀 is given by (𝐶 11 + 𝐶 12 )𝜀 2 , and equating the two strain energies we find:</p><formula xml:id="formula_7">1 3 (𝐶 11 + 𝐶 12 ) 𝐴 = 1 2 𝜅𝑎 s 2</formula><p>with 𝐴 being the unstrained area of a unit cell. Carrying out the computation, using the DFT lattice parameter, one concludes that for WSe2, the parameter</p><formula xml:id="formula_8">1 2</formula><p>𝜅𝑎 s 2 = 28.4 eV. Noting that we can stabilize a strained film with a surface corrugation at the atomic scale of 𝑉 o ≈ 5 × 10 -4 , we conclude that the film will be stable in the strained state if the corrugation at the atomic scale is of the order of 14 meV over the range of a single unit cell.</p><p>This required corrugation, then, sets a scale for the retention of thermal mismatch strain.</p><p>It is much less than a typical covalent bond strength (of the order of 1 eV). Interestingly, this corrugation is very near to the strength of a typical van der Waals bond (of the order of 20-40 meV). We conclude that a covalent bond between the atoms of the growing film and that of the substrate is not necessary to enable strain tuning of the film via thermal expansion mismatch.</p><p>The elastic constants of a monolayer of WSe2 were calculated using the plane-wave density functional theory (DFT) program VASP <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . Projector augmented wave potentials were used for the ion-electron interactions, 2 and the PBE generalized gradient approximation was used for the exchange-correlation functional 3 . The system modeled was a WSe2 monolayer, which was represented by a 3 atom cell with a 15.44 Å vacuum layer, normal to the monolayer. The plane wave energy cutoff was 600 eV, and the tetrahedron smearing method was used. The electronic</p><p>self-consistent loop's convergence criterion was set to 1 x 10 -8 , and the system was relaxed until the Hellmann-Feynman forces on each atom were below 0.001 eV Å -1 . A gamma centered 29 × 29 × 1 Monkhorst pack grid was used to sample k-space. First, the system was relaxed allowing the cell and atomic positions to change. The lattice parameter for monolayer WSe2 was found to be 3.316 Å. Using the relaxed system, the elastic constants were found using the method presented by de Jong et. al <ref type="bibr">4</ref> . The 2D elastic constants for monolayer WSe2 were calculated to be C11 = 120 J m -2 and C12 = 23 J m -2 .</p><p>Supplementary Note 2: Expected strain from lattice misfit.</p><p>Due to the fact that the WSe2 is not covalently bound to the growth substrate we would not expect the strain to be transferred from the mismatch between the lattice constant of the substrate and the 2D material. However, to verify this we calculated the expected strain due to lattice misfit.</p><p>The lattice misfit equation for heteroepitaxial strain is given by 5 :</p><formula xml:id="formula_10">𝑓 = 𝑎 Sub (𝑇) -𝑎 2D (𝑇) 𝑎 2D (𝑇)</formula><p>where aSub, a2D, and T are the lattice parameter of the substrate, the lattice parameter of the 2D material, and temperature respectively. In the case where f &gt; 0 the film is expected to be under tensile strain, while for the case where f &lt; 0 the film is expected to be under compressive strain. In our case we compute the expected lattice misfit both at room temperature as well as the growth temperature. The results are summarized in Supplementary Table <ref type="table">1</ref>, and indicate that we would expect that samples grown on AlN are under compressive strain while samples grown on Sapphire and STO are under tensile strain. This is highly inconsistent with the experimental results, which indicate that samples grown on AlN are under tensile strain, samples grown on STO are under compressive strain, and samples grown on Sapphire are relaxed, suggesting that the strain we observe in our samples does not originate from lattice mismatch.</p><p>(</p><formula xml:id="formula_11">)<label>4</label></formula><p>Layer control: We found that the temperature of the WO3/promoter boat plays a significant role in optimization of the WSe2 thickness. By varying the temperature of the WO3/promoter boat while keeping the other growth parameters constant, we could control the thickness of the material being grown. Synthesis initiated at 875°C results in predominantly monolayers domains. When the synthesis begins at 900°C, both WSe2 monolayer and bilayer are observed. Growth initiated at temperatures greater than 900°C result in multilayer growth. This behavior can be attributed to increasing tungsten vapor pressure at high temperatures. It is important to note that for WSe2 grown at different temperatures (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3 (c</ref>) and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5</ref>), the WO3/promoter boat and the target substrates were placed in separate furnace zones (shown schematically in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">7 (b)</ref>).</p><p>Device fabrication: Back-gated devices were fabricated on WSe2 samples grown on fused silica and transferred to Si/SiO2 (50 nm thick oxide) substrates as well as WSe2 directly exfoliated on Si/SiO2 (50 nm thick oxide) substrates to further verify material quality. All patterning was performed using electron beam lithography with PMMA C4 as the resist. Samples were first etched using XeF2, and subsequently 40 nm thick Ni was deposited by thermal evaporation as the contact electrode. Both CVD and exfoliated WSe2 devices show ambipolar behavior with similar on-currents as shown in Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">13</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ARTICLE</head><p>Strain-engineered growth of two-dimensional materials Geun Ho Ahn 1,2 , Matin Amani The application of strain to semiconductors allows for controlled modification of their band structure. This principle is employed for the manufacturing of devices ranging from highperformance transistors to solid-state lasers. Traditionally, strain is typically achieved via growth on lattice-mismatched substrates. For two-dimensional (2D) semiconductors, this is not feasible as they typically do not interact epitaxially with the substrate. Here, we demonstrate controlled strain engineering of 2D semiconductors during synthesis by utilizing the thermal coefficient of expansion mismatch between the substrate and semiconductor.</p><p>Using WSe 2 as a model system, we demonstrate stable built-in strains ranging from 1% tensile to 0.2% compressive on substrates with different thermal coefficient of expansion. Consequently, we observe a dramatic modulation of the band structure, manifested by a strain-driven indirect-to-direct bandgap transition and brightening of the dark exciton in bilayer and monolayer WSe 2 , respectively. The growth method developed here should enable flexibility in design of more sophisticated devices based on 2D materials.</p><p>T wo-dimensional (2D) transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDCs) have been the subject of focused research owing to their potential applications in optoelectronics and sub 10 nm transistors <ref type="bibr">1,</ref><ref type="bibr">2</ref> . The primary attraction of TMDCs such as MoS 2 and WSe 2 for both applications is their naturally terminated surface, which allows them to be scaled down to the atomic limit without the concern of surface dangling bonds. Furthermore, in many 2D materials, a number of desirable properties emerge at the monolayer limit, the most notable of which being the presence of a direct bandgap. Many studies based on mechanical bending of exfoliated 2D TMDCs have been conducted on flexible substrates, and they have shown that the application of strain can tune the properties of this new class of materials <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref><ref type="bibr">[4]</ref><ref type="bibr">[5]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[6]</ref> . For example, it has been demonstrated that in multilayer WSe 2 , particularly in nominally indirect-gap bilayer WSe 2 , application of tensile strain can result in a transition from an indirect-to-direct bandgap <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">7</ref> . However, studies on the effects of strain in TMDCs have been limited to mechanical bending of samples, and there has yet to be a technique, which can directly realize built-in tensile and compressive strains.</p><p>Traditionally, strain engineering of semiconductors has been leveraged to tune the electronic band structure of high-performance devices, the most notable of which being to reduce intervalley scattering, increase mobility in Si transistors, and reduce the hole effective mass in III-V semiconductor lasers <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">9</ref> . Growth on epitaxial substrates with a controlled lattice constant mismatch has typically been utilized to establish built-in strain in three-dimensional semiconductors <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">10</ref> . However, due to the relatively weak interaction between 2D materials and substrates, this established method of strain engineering is likely not applicable for the strain-engineered growth of TMDCs. Therefore, a route toward development of large-area strained TMDCs on a practical substrate is highly desirable. Significant research efforts have been made to realize large area TMDCs, with the majority of efforts focusing on chemical vapor deposition (CVD) <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[13]</ref> . Interestingly, a number of studies employing CVD growth of 2D materials have reported apparent strain in the synthesized samples <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">15</ref> .</p><p>However, growth of high-quality 2D materials with controllable built-in strain has not been realized. Hence, properties that are difficult to probe via mechanical bending experiments, such as low-temperature optical measurements and electrical performance, have yet to be explored.</p><p>In this work, we demonstrate strain engineering of 2D materials directly via CVD growth while simultaneously maintaining high material quality, by utilizing the thermal coefficient of expansion (TCE) mismatch between the TMDC and the growth substrate. Electron diffraction of strained monolayers grown directly onto transmission electron microscopy (TEM) windows is utilized to unambiguously quantify strain. Using WSe 2 as a model system, we show that it is possible to obtain both tensile (of ~1%) and compressive (0.2%) strained 2D semiconductors over large areas on rigid substrates. Furthermore, in the WSe 2 model system we show indirect-to-direct optical transition in tensile strained WSe 2 bilayers as well as removal of dark exciton quenching in WSe 2 monolayers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>TCE-mismatch induced strain. Owing to the high growth temperatures used to synthesize TMDCs, the TCE mismatch between the substrate and the 2D semiconductor can be utilized to control the strain in the synthesized 2D material, as shown schematically in Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>. The theoretical upper limit for the strain, assuming no relaxation, can be calculated using the difference in lattice constant of the substrate and 2D semiconductor at room temperature and synthesis temperature:</p><formula xml:id="formula_12">ε T g À Á ¼ a 2D T g À Á À a 2D 25 C ð Þ a 2D 25 C ð Þ À a Sub T g À Á À a Sub 25 C ð Þ a Sub 25 C ð Þ<label>ð1Þ</label></formula><p>where a 2D is the in-plane lattice constant for the 2D material being grown, a Sub is the in-plane lattice constant of the substrate, and T g is the growth temperature. More generally, this can be calculated using the temperature dependent thermal expansion coefficient for the 2D material (α 2D ) and substrate (α Sub ) Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref> Strain-engineered growth of WSe 2 using TCE-mismatch. Schematic of the process through which strain is realized during the growth of 2D materials via mismatch in substrate and TMDC thermal expansion coefficient. a Tensile strain is achieved when the TCE of the substrate is less than that of the 2D material, b relaxed samples are achieved when the TCE of the substrate and 2D material match, and c compressive strain is achieved when the TCE of the substrate is greater than that of the 2D material according to:</p><formula xml:id="formula_13">ε T g À Á ¼ Z T g 25 C α 2D T ð ÞdT À Z T g 25 C α Sub T ð ÞdT<label>ð2Þ</label></formula><p>To retain the strain generated from TCE-mismatch, the bonding between the 2D layer and the substrate must be sufficiently strong and corrugated to maintain the nonslip condition that transmits strain to the layer. Although one expects strains of this magnitude to arise during epitaxial growth, it is difficult to see how a similar strain can arise for films bound by van der Waals forces to an amorphous substrate. Experimentally, the corrugation in the film must be large enough to retain the strain upon cooling. To estimate the magnitude of the corrugation necessary to sustain the strain, we analyzed a 2D Frenkel-Kontorova model <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">16</ref> , shown in Supplementary Note 1 and Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">1</ref>. This model suggests that atomic binding energy variations of as little as 14 meV over the range of the unit cell are capable of retaining strains of the magnitude of those observed experimentally. This variation is ~1% of a typical covalent bond strength, and very near to the typical strength of a van der Waals bond. Though a more detailed theory needs to be developed, especially to understand the surface chemistry immediately prior to growth to determine the nature of the bonding, this simple analysis suggests that thermal-expansion mismatch can strain a film, even in the case of weak binding between the film and the substrate. It should be noted that in a previous study, local heating of MoS 2 using a laser was used to generate strains of up to 0.2% arising from the TCE-mismatch of MoS 2 with the substrate <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">17</ref> . Although this method does not generate built-in strains (strain is released once the laser is turned off), it suggests that the MoS 2 -substrate bonding is strong enough to enable TCE-mismatched induced strain engineering <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">17</ref> .</p><p>To demonstrate strain-engineered CVD growth of WSe 2 , four substrates were chosen, which have a range of TCEs. Fused silica and aluminum nitride (AlN) have a TCE of 0.55 and 5.5 ppm, respectively, much smaller than that of WSe 2 (9.5 ± 3.2 ppm), and would be expected to induce tensile strain <ref type="bibr">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[19]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[22]</ref> . In contrast, sapphire has a TCE closely matched to WSe 2 and would be expected to produce relaxed samples and strontium titanate (STO) with a TCE of 12 ppm should yield compressively strained samples <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">24</ref> . The sample was rapidly quenched after growth to limit relaxation in the WSe 2 . It is important to note that the rapid quenching process was found to be important in maintaining the presence of strain, and delay of the quenching step can result in partial relaxation of the 2D material.</p><p>Characterization strain and material quality. To characterize the strain present in the as-grown material, multiple characterization methods were utilized. First, electron diffraction was performed on WSe 2 as-grown on SiO 2 TEM grids and WSe 2 transferred to SiO 2 TEM grids. The resulting diffraction patterns are shown in Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2a-c</ref>. In all TEM diffraction measurements on WSe 2 , the camera length and lens aberrations of the imaging systems were calibrated using polycrystalline aluminum and single crystal aluminum calibration samples (Ted Pella), and the microscope lens settings were left constant for all subsequent measurements. Corresponding images and photoluminescence (PL) spectra of the samples in Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2b,</ref><ref type="figure">c</ref> are shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">2</ref>. By comparing the lattice constant extracted from the diffraction patterns of strained (as-grown) and unstrained (transferred) WSe 2 , and utilizing the center of mass for 75 diffraction spots from each pattern, we calculate that a 1.39 ± 0.28% tensile strain is present in the as-grown sample. The calculated error represents the standard deviation in lattice constant value over 75 measured diffraction spots. Raman spectrum shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2d</ref> reveals a shift of the E' in-plane Raman mode of 1.5 ± 0.2 cm -1 between as-grown and transferred WSe 2 . We note that the strain measured here is biaxial, not uniaxial, in contrast to mechanical bending studies and thus we do not observe splitting of the E′ mode. Therefore, the theoretically calculated value for the Grüneisen parameter (χ) of WSe 2 is used to calculate the expected peak shift according to: ω ε ð Þ ¼ ω 0 þ χε, which is consistent with the approximately 1% tensile strain measured via diffraction <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[25]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[26]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[27]</ref> . It should also be noted that after transfer the E' mode shows no shift relative to samples prepared either by exfoliation or as-grown on sapphire. High resolution Raman mapping was performed and is shown in Figs. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2e,</ref><ref type="figure">f</ref> for WSe 2 crystals as-grown on fused silica and transferred to a new fused silica substrate, respectively. We observe a uniform Raman shift throughout the full WSe 2 domain for both samples indicating that the strain is uniformly distributed within the sample on the scale of the Raman spot size. In addition, PL and atomic force microscopy images of as-grown WSe 2 on fused silica are shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3</ref>.</p><p>PL measurements were employed to measure the bandgap as a function of strain. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3a</ref> shows PL spectra of samples grown on all substrates investigated in this work as well as an exfoliated reference. There is a large spectral shift of 120 meV between samples grown on fused silica with near zero TCE and STO, which has the highest TCE of all substrates investigated in this work. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3b</ref> shows the estimated strain from the PL peak shift as a function of predicted strain in WSe 2 , vs. the lattice mismatch between the substrate and TMDC lattice constant. Strain values are determined from the experimentally measured PL peak position (measurement error was calculated using the standard deviation of strain measured from fifteen different crystals) and theoretically calculated bandgap as a function of strain extracted from refs <ref type="bibr">3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">27</ref> . It is important to note that we utilized the difference in peak position relative to an unstrained sample to eliminate effects from absolute bandgap error relative to theoretical calculations. We performed an analysis of the expected strain due to lattice parameter misfit (Supplementary Table <ref type="table">1</ref> and Supplementary Note 2) to rule out the influence of epitaxial strain between the substrate and WSe 2 . From this calculation, the expected strain from the lattice mismatch shows the opposite trend as compared with what we observe experimentally. We find that our experimentally realized strain per ΔTCE of -0.10 ± 0.01% per ppm K -1 is in excellent agreement with the theoretical value of -0.09% per ppm K -1 . To verify that the substrate does not affect the PL peak shape or position of monolayer WSe 2 , samples were transferred to the four substrates used in this study (Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4</ref>) and no shift of the PL peak was observed. The impact of growth temperature to tune the strain was also studied using fused silica as the substrate. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3c</ref> shows the tensile strain in monolayer WSe 2 grown at different temperatures, estimated using PL peak position. We are able to tune the strain from 0.94 ± 0.06% to 0.67 ± 0.05% as the growth temperature is changed from 900 to 673 °C. PL spectra corresponding to Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3c</ref> is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5</ref>.</p><p>Tensile strain engineering of mono-and bilayer WSe 2 . Calibrated PL measurements were used to provide a gauge of material quality. We find that strained WSe 2 monolayers as-grown on fused silica show comparable PL intensity to exfoliated WSe 2 , demonstrating that strain engineering of 2D materials can be achieved without compromising material performance. Specifically, as exfoliated samples show a typical quantum yield (QY) of 2.3 ± 0.4%, while samples grown on fused silica show a typical QY of 1.9 ± 0.6%. Upon transfer, the strain within the as-grown material is released and its emission peak shifts to 1.65 eV, closely matching that of exfoliated samples, as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4a</ref>. In addition to emission, the absorption spectrum of the as-grown monolayer was measured and is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4b</ref>. The absorption spectra clearly shows that the A and B exciton resonances are red- shifted with the presence of tensile strain, and are consistent with the observed shift in the emission. Interestingly, the absorption of the C exciton peak shows no shift between the as-grown and exfoliated samples, which is consistent with previously reported mechanical bending experiments on exfoliated monolayers, although it should be noted that in these experiments the strain was uniaxial <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">28</ref> . More interestingly, it has been previously demonstrated using bending experiments that under the application of a uniaxial strain of ~1.5%, bilayer WSe 2 undergoes an indirect-to-direct bandgap transition <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">7</ref> . This effect is caused by an increase in the energy level of the indirect valley at the Σ point as well as a corresponding decrease in the energy level of the direct valley at the K point <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">7</ref> . While it is important to note these results are obtained under uniaxial strain, similar trends between uniaxial and biaxial strain have been observed in theoretical studies on other 2D material systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">29</ref> . Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4c</ref> depicts the PL spectra of as-grown, exfoliated and transferred bilayer WSe 2 . In the asgrown strained bilayer, we observe a single sharp PL peak, as oppose to a broader spectrum corresponding to emission from both the indirect and direct bandgaps observed in the unstrained exfoliated and transferred samples. Moreover, the intensity of the PL is reduced by approximately 50 times upon transfer and resultant release of tensile strain as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4c</ref>. This phenomenon can possibly be attributed to the optical transition from indirect-to-direct in bilayer WSe 2 in the presence of tensile strain. This is in good agreement with previous reports on the indirect-to-direct optical transition of WSe 2 through bending experiments, although these previous studies utilized uniaxial strain <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">7</ref> . The normalized PL spectra for bilayer WSe 2 grown on fused silica after transfer, as well as unstrained samples grown on sapphire and prepared by exfoliation, are shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">6</ref> and show a very similar spectral shape. Absorption of WSe 2 bilayer samples was also measured and is shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">4d</ref>.</p><p>To further characterize WSe 2 monolayers, we performed low-temperature PL measurements. Numerous studies have experimentally observed that the PL of monolayer WSe 2 is quenched at reduced temperatures. This behavior is unusual for a direct bandgap semiconductor and has been attributed to the formation of dark excitons with an energy level ~30 meV below the bright state <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">31</ref> . It has been hypothesized that at low temperatures the bright exciton is allowed to relax to the lower energy level resulting in a reduction of the PL QY. Conversely, both theoretical and experimental studies have suggested that unstrained monolayer WSe 2 is an indirect-gap semiconductor, with a small (&lt; 3kT) energy difference between the indirect and direct gaps <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">33</ref> . Upon cooling of exfoliated monolayer WSe 2 samples, we observe results similar to what has been previously reported as shown in the inset of Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5a</ref>, which is a reduction in PL emission at low temperatures. However, for the case of tensile strained monolayer WSe 2 as-grown on fused silica we observe the opposite trend (Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5</ref>). As the temperature is reduced from 300 to 6 K the PL intensity increases by over an order of magnitude, resulting in a final PL QY of 14% as shown in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">5d</ref>. The nature of the physical mechanism for the dramatic difference in the temperaturedependent behavior can be directly attributed to band structure modification due to the presence of strain. However, it remains unclear if this is due to an indirect-to-direct bandgap transition or an increase in the energy level of the dark state.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Discussion</head><p>In summary, we have demonstrated controlled and stable strain engineering of 2D materials by growth, realized through TCE mismatch between the substrate and 2D material. The demonstrated strain engineering allows for dramatic modulation of the physical properties of 2D materials. Using WSe 2 as a model system, we have achieved a strain induced indirect-to-direct optical transition in directly grown WSe 2 bilayer, resulting in an amplification of the PL intensity by over fifty times. We have also shown tunable PL emission of WSe 2 monolayer, whereas maintaining its high performance. Notably, in the monolayer case under tensile strain, we observed increasing luminescence at reduced temperatures, in stark contrast with what has been reported in the unstrained exfoliated material, suggesting that strain can be utilized to brighten the dark exciton. This practical route for the direct realization of strain engineering in 2D materials can allow for the characterization of device properties as a function of strain as well as enable optical measurements that are not accessible to samples strained by physical bending or stretching. Our work depicts that biaxial strains of 1% tensile to 0.2% compressive can be obtained by using readily achievable differences in the thermal expansion coefficients by choosing an appropriate growth substrate. By expanding upon this method, it may be possible to obtain uniaxial strain via growth on substrates with anisotropic thermal expansion coefficients or obtain significantly higher strain values via growth on piezoelectric substrates <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">35</ref> .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Methods</head><p>Material growth. WSe 2 was grown on several substrates with varying thermal expansion coefficients using CVD. Specifically, growth was performed on fused silica (amorphous), aluminum nitride (c-plane), Sapphire (c-plane), or strontium titanate (&lt;100&gt;); all substrates were electronic grade and have a root mean square surface roughness of &lt;10 Å. Substrates were first cleaned by sonication in acetone and isopropyl alcohol for 10 min. The growth was carried out using a two-heatingzone furnace (DaePoong Industry, 50602); a schematic of the growth setup is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">7</ref>. The cleaned substrates were loaded into the downstream zone, and a ceramic boat containing mixture of WO 3 and potassium bromide (KBr) was then placed next to the substrates. KBr was mixed with WO 3 at a ratio of 1:2, with the KBr acting as a promoter for the growth. This is similar to methods described in ref. <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">36</ref> . However, we found that several salts can be used and the choice of promoter has a significant role in determining the ultimate sample morphology (this is further discussed in the Supplementary Methods). It should be noted that regardless of the promoter used, the strain present in the sample was unaffected as shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure">8</ref>. A ceramic boat containing 500 mg Se powder was placed in the center of the upstream zone. After loading, the quartz tube was evacuated and Ar was introduced at 60 sccm resulting in a pressure of 2.6 Torr. The temperature of upstream zone was then ramped to 100 °C and the downstream furnace was subsequently ramped to a setpoint of 825 °C. The set point of the upstream zone was adjusted such that the residual heat from the downstream zone results in vaporization of Se. Once the temperature of downstream furnace was stabilized, hydrogen was introduced at a flow rate of 40 sccm (total pressure of 3 Torr). This initiates the growth as the presence of hydrogen is required to decompose and vaporize WO x <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">37</ref> . The growth time used was 15 min. Once the growth is complete, hydrogen flow was stopped, and the furnace was opened to rapidly cool the sample. The influence of the H 2 /Ar ratio, growth time and growth pressure is discussed in the Supplementary Methods and are shown in Supplementary Figs 9-11. Optical microscope images of samples grown on various substrates is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">12</ref>. Specific growth conditions were tuned to optimize the PL QY of the as-grown samples and to either promote growth of bilayer or monolayer domains (discussed in Supplementary Methods). It should be noted that for growths where the substrate temperature was varied the WO 3 /KBr boat was placed in the center of the first heating zone and the Se boat was placed at the edge of the first heating zone. The substrates were placed in the center of the second heating zone. The position of Se boat was adjusted to control the temperature. Transfer of grown WSe 2 is done using a HF based wet transfer technique with PMMA as the transfer medium using the specific procedure described in ref. <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">11</ref> . The electrical performance of CVD WSe 2 grown on fused silica and transferred to Si/SiO 2 is also compared to that of exfoliated samples, and is shown in Supplementary Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">13</ref>.</p><p>Transmission electron microscopy. WSe 2 monolayers were directly grown and transferred on 8 nm thick SiO 2 membranes (Ted Pella) for electron diffraction measurements in order to directly measure the lattice constant of the strained and unstrained samples, respectively. Electron diffraction measurements were Optical characterization. The PL data presented in this work was obtained using a custom built micro-PL instrument described in detail in ref. <ref type="bibr">1</ref> . In brief, measurements were performed using the continuous wave 514.5 nm line of an Ar + laser (Lexel 95) and the laser power was adjusted using neutral density filters. The laser was focused on the sample using an 80 × objective lens (NA = 0.9). The PL signal was measured using the same objective lens, passed through a 550 nm dielectric longpass filter, dispersed by a f = 340 mm spectrometer with a 150 g mm -1 grating, and detected using by an Si CCD camera (Andor iDus BEX2-DD). Prior to each measurement the CCD background was obtained and subsequently subtracted from the PL acquisition. The sensitivity of the instrument as a function of wavelength (instrument function) was determined through measurement of a virtual Lambertian blackbody source under the objective, created by imaging the illumination from a temperature stabilized lamp (ThorLabs SLS201) on a diffuse reflector (Spectralon). The system efficiency was determined by measuring the response of the excitation laser focused onto a diffuse reflector (Spectralon), with the 550 nm longpass filter removed. The measured external quantum efficiency was converted to QY using sample absorption at the pump wavelength and the fraction of light, which is able to escape the sample (1/4n 2 , where n is the refractive index of the medium). All measurements shown in this work were performed at an incident power of 1.5 W cm -2 (corresponding to a laser power of 200 nW). This laser power is significantly below the onset of biexcitonic recombination in WSe 2 <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">38</ref> . Low temperature measurements were performed using a long working distance 50 × objective lens in a micro-cryostat (Janis) with an infrasil window. The procedure described previously was used to calculate the sample PL efficiency. PL imaging was performed on the samples to determine their uniformity. Measurements were performed using a florescence microscopy setup using a 470 nm light emitting diode as the excitation source and a CCD detector (Andor Luca). Raman measurements and high-resolution mapping were performed to characterize the strain in the WSe 2 . Raman spectra were obtained using a WITec Alpha 300RA equipped with a piezo electric scanning stage. The sample was excited using the 532 nm line of a frequency-doubled Nd:YAG laser as the excitation source and focused on the sample using a 100 × objective.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>2 𝑖</head><label>2</label><figDesc>𝐸 potential = ∑ (|𝐫 𝑖 -𝐫 𝑗 | -𝑎 o )</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Fig. 2</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Fig. 2 Transmission electron microscopy images and Raman spectroscopy of monolayer WSe 2 . a Overlay of diffraction spots for as-grown and transferred monolayer WSe 2 , showing a 1.39 ± 0.28% strain in samples grown directly on the TEM membrane. Scale bar is 10 nm -1 . b Electron diffraction patterns of a tensile strained WSe 2 monolayer grown directly on an 8 nm SiO 2 TEM membrane and c a WSe 2 monolayer transferred to the same thickness membrane. Scale bar is 10 nm -1 . d Raman spectra of WSe 2 monolayers grown on various substrates. e, f Raman mapping of E' peak position for a (e) tensile strained WSe 2 monolayer as-grown on fused silica and a (f) WSe 2 monolayer transferred to release strain; data are plotted using the same false color scheme. Scale bar is 20 μm, data range is 250.5 to 247.0 cm -1</figDesc><graphic coords="26,115.18,226.16,350.20,73.72" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Fig. 3</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Fig. 3 Strain engineering of 2D materials. a PL spectra for monolayer WSe 2 as-grown on substrates with a range of thermal coefficient of expansion mismatches. b Estimated strain that can be achieved in 2D materials based on the mismatch between the substrate and TMDC thermal coefficient of expansion; data points show measured strain for substrates with a range of thermal expansion coefficient mismatch; dashed gray lines are based on TCE values for WSe 2 obtained from refs 21, 22 , dashed black line shows fit to experimental data. c Estimated strain realized in WSe 2 as-grown on fused silica at various substrate temperatures; dashed gray lines are based on TCE values for WSe 2 obtained from refs 21, 22 , dashed black line shows fit to experimental data. Error bars indicate standard deviation of strain, measured over fifteen samples</figDesc><graphic coords="27,361.03,395.78,158.68,129.76" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Fig. 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Photon energy (eV) 1.7 1.8 1.4 0</figDesc><graphic coords="28,168.61,63.74,124.60,101.92" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Fig. 5</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Photoluminescence (counts s -1)</figDesc><graphic coords="29,145.69,64.22,144.28,117.52" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="1,72.00,116.20,467.90,180.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="2,72.00,72.00,468.00,177.05" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="3,72.00,72.00,468.00,193.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="4,135.75,72.00,340.07,274.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="5,135.00,72.00,341.58,277.75" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="6,142.23,72.00,327.53,268.85" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="7,72.00,72.00,468.00,398.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="8,135.75,72.00,340.50,274.40" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="9,72.00,72.00,468.00,108.45" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="11,72.00,72.00,468.00,110.60" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="12,72.00,72.00,468.00,108.20" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic coords="13,130.50,72.00,350.25,278.97" type="bitmap" /></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" xml:id="foot_0"><p>NATURE COMMUNICATIONS | 8: 608| DOI: 10.1038/s41467-017-00516-5 | www.nature.com/naturecommunications</p></note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div><head>Acknowledgements</head><p>The authors would like to thank <rs type="person">Ian S. Winter</rs> for providing them with his elastic constants code that interfaces with VASP. Materials growth, characterization, and modeling were supported by the <rs type="funder">U.S. Department of Energy, Office of Science, Office of Basic Energy Sciences, Materials Sciences and Engineering Division</rs> under contract no. <rs type="grantNumber">DE-AC02-05CH11231</rs> within the <rs type="programName">Electronic Materials Program</rs> (<rs type="grantNumber">KC1201</rs>). Electron Microscopy was performed at the Molecular Foundry which is supported by the <rs type="funder">Office of Science, Office of Basic Energy Sciences</rs>, of the <rs type="funder">U.S. Department of Energy</rs> under Contract No. <rs type="grantNumber">DE-AC02-05CH11231</rs>.</p></div>
			</div>
			<listOrg type="funding">
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_mJD4BqA">
					<idno type="grant-number">DE-AC02-05CH11231</idno>
					<orgName type="program" subtype="full">Electronic Materials Program</orgName>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_hrqmqtj">
					<idno type="grant-number">KC1201</idno>
				</org>
				<org type="funding" xml:id="_j9B646Z">
					<idno type="grant-number">DE-AC02-05CH11231</idno>
				</org>
			</listOrg>

			<div type="availability">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Data availability. The data that support the findings of this study are available from the corresponding author on request.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Figures</head><p>Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>   </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Notes</head><p>Supplementary Note 1: Frenkel-Kontorova Model to Explore Retention of Thermal-Expansion Mismatch Strains.</p><p>When viewed in the light of epitaxy, the thermal expansion mismatch strain observed in the samples is noteworthy, particularly in the case of the amorphous fused silica. With an amorphous substrate, one does not expect epitaxy, and hence one does not expect epitaxial strain.</p><p>However, the amorphous substrate still represents a corrugated potential, albeit without long-range crystalline order, for the deposited film. It is interesting, then, to consider the amplitude of the corrugation necessary to sustain the thermal-expansion mismatch strain within the films. In order to explore the amplitude of the surface corrugation required to retain the strain arising due to thermal expansion mismatch, we explored a simple 2D Frenkel-Kontorova model <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">16</ref> . Though the model is simple, it provides substantial insight into the considered problem, and enables exploration of the large systems. Though the model is best suited for epitaxy, it does allow exploration of the relationship between the corrugation of the potential and the retention of thermal mismatch strain.</p><p>The 2D Frenkel-Kontorova model considered here consists of a single plane of atoms connected by springs interacting with a substrate potential that has the same triangular symmetry (Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">1 (a)</ref>). One can think of these atoms as representing the plane of Se atoms in contact with the substrate. The springs strengths model the effective interactions between these atoms, that are, of course, determined by the layers W and Se atoms not indirect contact with the substrate. In dimensionless form, where all lengths are measured in terms of the substrate lattice parameter, as, and all energies measured in terms</p><p>𝜅𝑎 s 2 , with 𝜅 the spring constant of the model, the potential energy of the system can be written as:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supplementary Methods</head><p>The furnace temperature profile as a function of the set point temperature for both zones was characterized to determine the actual sample temperature as well as the cross talk between furnace zones. This was used to adjust the set point of the upstream zone such that the selenium powder would reach the target temperature from excess heat provided by the downstream zone as well as to determine the actual temperature of the growth as compared to the furnace set point. A schematic of the furnace setup used for all growths performed in this study is shown in Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">7</ref>. For various substrates, several modifications were made to the general procedure used to grow monolayer samples on fused silica described in the main text. Optical images of WSe2 grown on various substrates, as well as the dependence of growth morphology on Ar/H2 ratio, growth time, and gas pressure are shown in Supplementary Figures 9, 10, 11, and 12   respectively. Additionally, photoluminescence imaging and atomic force microscopy were performed to verify sample uniformity and is shown in Supplementary Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Growth on AlN:</head><p>NaBr is employed as a promotor for the growth of WSe2 instead of KBr. NaBr is mixed with WO3 at 1:2 ratio. All the other growth parameters are kept the same as the method described in the manuscript.</p><p>Growth on sapphire (Al 2 O 3 ): NaCl or KBr is used as a promotor for the growth of WSe2 on sapphire. The promotor is mixed with WO3 at the ratio of 1:2. All the other growth parameters are kept the same as the method described in the manuscript.</p><p>Growth on STO: NaBr is mixed with WO3 at the ratio of 1:2. As the downstream furnace temperature reaches 875°C, the synthesis of the WSe2 is initiated by introducing hydrogen. All the other growth parameters are kept the same as the method described in the manuscript. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Additional information</head><p>Supplementary Information accompanies this paper at doi:10.1038/s41467-017-00516-5.</p><p>Competing interests: The authors declare no competing financial interests.</p><p>Reprints and permission information is available online at <ref type="url" target="http://npg.nature.com/reprintsandpermissions/">http://npg.nature.com/ reprintsandpermissions/</ref> Publisher's note: Springer Nature remains neutral with regard to jurisdictional claims in published maps and institutional affiliations.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ab initio molecular dynamics for liquid metals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kresse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Hafner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="558" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From ultrasoft pseudopotentials to the projector augmented -wave method</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Kresse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Joubert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1758</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Generalized gradient approximation made simple</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Perdew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Ernzerhof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Burke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3865" to="3868" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">First-principles study of the structural and elastic properties of rhenium-based transition-metal alloys</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>De Jong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Olmsted</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Van De Walle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Asta</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">224101</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Heteroepitaxy of Semiconductors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Ayers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boca Raton, FL</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Near-unity photoluminescence quantum yield in MoS 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Amani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">350</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1065" to="1068" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">MoS 2 transistors with 1-nanometer gate lengths</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Desai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">354</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Orbital analysis of electronic structure and phonon dispersion in MoS 2 , MoSe 2 , WS 2 , and WSe 2 monolayers under strain</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C.-H</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Fan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S.-H</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J.-L</forename><surname>Kuo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">195420</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quasiparticle band structures and optical properties of strained monolayer MoS 2 and WS 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Shi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y.-W</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Yakobson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">155304</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Structural phase transitions in two-dimensional Mo-and W-dichalcogenide monolayers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K.-A</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Duerloo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Reed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">4214</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Observation of piezoelectricity in free-standing monolayer MoS 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Nano</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="155" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strain-induced indirect to direct bandgap transition in multilayer WSe 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Desai</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4592" to="4597" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">90-nm logic technology featuring strained-silicon</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Trans. Electron Dev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1790" to="1797" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Band structure engineering of semiconductor lasers for optical communications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Yablonovitch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Kane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Lightw. Technol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1292" to="1299" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nanometre-scale electronics with III-V compound semiconductors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Alamo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">479</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="317" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grains and grain boundaries in highly crystalline monolayer molybdenum disulphide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Zande</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Mat</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="554" to="561" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Synthesis of high quality two-dimensional materials via chemical vapor deposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6705" to="6716" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High-mobility three-atom-thick semiconducting films with wafer-scale homogeneity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Kang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">520</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="656" to="660" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strain and structure heterogeneity in MoS 2 atomic layers grown by chemical vapour deposition</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Commun</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5246</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Growth-substrate induced performance degradation in chemically synthesized monolayer MoS 2 field effect transistors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Amani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">104</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">203506</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kivshar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Frenkel-Kontorova Model-Concepts, Method, and Applications</title>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Control of biaxial strain in single-layer molybdenite using local thermal expansion of the substrate. 2D Mater</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Plechinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">15006</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Very low thermal expansion coefficient materials</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Agrawal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mckinstry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annu. Rev. Mater. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thermal expansion of some diamondlike crystals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Slack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Bartram</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="1975">1975</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lattice parameters and thermal expansion of important semiconductors and their substrates</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Reeber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mat. Res. Soc. Symp</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">662</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The thermal expansion of 2H-MoS 2 , 2H-MoSe 2 , and 2H-WSe 2 between 20 and 800 °C</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>El-Mahalawy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Cryst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="406" />
			<date type="published" when="1976">1976</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Thermal expansion tensors, Grüneisen parameters and photon velocities of bulk MT 2 (M=W and Mo; T=S and Se) from first principle calculations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Xiao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<publisher>RSC Adv</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18391" to="18400" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thermal expansion of AlN, sapphire, and silicon</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Yim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Paff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Phys</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1456" to="1457" />
			<date type="published" when="1974">1974</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High temperature heat capacity and thermal expansion of SrTiO 3 and SrZrO 3 perovskites</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Ligny</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Richet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3013" to="3022" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Thermal expansion, anharmonicity and temperature dependent Raman spectra of single-and few-layer MoSe 2 and WSe 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Late</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Shirodkar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Waghmare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dravid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">N R</forename><surname>Rao</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Chem. Phys. Chem</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1592" to="1598" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anomalous Raman spectra and thickness-dependent electronic properties of WSe 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sahin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">165409</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tuning the electronic properties of semiconducting transition metal dichalcogenides by applying mechanical strains</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Johari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Shenoy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACS Nano</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5449" to="5456" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reversible uniaxial strain tuning in atomically thin WSe 2 . 2D Mat</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">21011</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Theoretical study on strain-induced variation in electronic properties of MoS 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Dong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Namburu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>O'regan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Dubey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dongare</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Mat. Sci</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6762" to="6771" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Experimental evidence for dark excitons in monolayer WSe 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X.-X</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">115</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">257403</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probing excitonic dark states in single-layer tungsten disulphide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Ye</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">513</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="214" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Large excitonic effects in monolayers of molybdenum and tungsten dichalcogenides</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ramasubramaniam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Phys. Rev. B</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">115409</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Probing critical point energies of transition metal dichalcogenides: surprising indirect gap of single layer WSe 2</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6494" to="6500" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nanostructured crystals: Unique hybrid semiconductors exhibiting nearly zero and tunable uniaxial thermal expansion behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Ki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reddy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Am. Chem. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">129</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14140" to="14141" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anisotropy of thermal expansion in YAlO 3 and NdGaO 3</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Chaix-Pluchery</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Chenevier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Robles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Phys. Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">251911</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Halide-assisted atmospheric pressure growth of large area WSe 2 and WS 2 monolayer crystals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl. Mater. Today</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chemical vapor deposition of large-sized hexagonal WSe 2 crystals on dielectric substrates</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adv. Matter</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6722" to="6727" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Recombination kinetics and effects of superacid treatment in sulfur-and selenium based transition metal dichalcogenides</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Amani</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nano Lett</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2786" to="2791" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
